{
    "questions": [
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1946",
                "B. 1974",
                "C. 1951",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "The Assam Public Service Commission (APSC) Regulation was promulgated in exercise of the powers __.",
            "answer": "C. 1951"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jorhat",
                "B. Golaghat",
                "C. Sibsagar",
                "D. Dhemaji"
            ],
            "question": "The first stadium of Assam was built in __.",
            "answer": "A. Jorhat"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jamindar",
                "B. King",
                "C. Frontier Officer",
                "D. Naval Commander"
            ],
            "question": "Sadiya Khowa Gohain was a __.",
            "answer": "D. Naval Commander"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Dr. Maheswar Neog",
                "B. Dr. Birinchi Kumar Barua",
                "C. Dr. surya Kumar Bhuyan",
                "D. Alexander Mackenzie"
            ],
            "question": "Prachya Sasanavali was edited by __.",
            "answer": "A. Dr. Maheswar Neog"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Chandraprabha Saikiani",
                "B. Pushpalata Das",
                "C. Rani Gaidinlieu",
                "D. Kanaklata Barua"
            ],
            "question": "During freedom struggle, the \"Mrityu Bahini\" was formed by __.",
            "answer": "B. Pushpalata Das"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Rudra Singha",
                "B. Rajeswar Singha",
                "C. Pramatta Singha",
                "D. Siv Singha"
            ],
            "question": "\"Rang Ghar\" was constructed during the reign of __.",
            "answer": "C. Pramatta Singha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1921",
                "B. 1932",
                "C. 1904",
                "D. 1911"
            ],
            "question": "When was Assam Provincial Congress Committee formed?",
            "answer": "A. 1921"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Nathan Brown",
                "B. Jatindranath Duara",
                "C. Devendranath Bezbarua",
                "D. Gunabhiram Barua"
            ],
            "question": "The author of \"Asomiya Sahityar Buranji\" is __.",
            "answer": "C. Devendranath Bezbarua"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1862",
                "B. 1874",
                "C. 1872",
                "D. 1863"
            ],
            "question": "The Assam region was separated from the Bengal Presidency as \"North-East Frontier\" in the year__.",
            "answer": "B. 1874"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Suryakhari Daibaigya",
                "B. Sukumar Borkaith",
                "C. Dibar and Ddosai",
                "D. Rama Saraswati"
            ],
            "question": "The illustration work of the medieval Assamese text \"Hastividyarnava\" was done by __.",
            "answer": "B. Sukumar Borkaith"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Nara Narayan",
                "B. Parikshit Narayan",
                "C. Viswa Singha",
                "D. Raghu Dev"
            ],
            "question": "The Gohain Kamal Ali road was constructed during the reign of __.",
            "answer": "A. Nara Narayan"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Siva Singha",
                "B. Pratap Singha",
                "C. Jayadhwaj Singha",
                "D. Suhungmung"
            ],
            "question": "The first Ahom Monarch to assume the Hindu title \"Swarganarayan\" was __.",
            "answer": "D. Suhungmung"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Aniram Dewan",
                "B. Piyali Baruah",
                "C. Gomdhar Knowar",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "The first rebellion against the British rule in Assam in 1828 was led by __.",
            "answer": "C. Gomdhar Knowar"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Dr. Hiren Gohain",
                "B. Dr. Mamani Roysom Goswami",
                "C. Homen Borgohain",
                "D. Dr. Sanjib Barua"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the author of the book 'India against Itself'?",
            "answer": "D. Dr. Sanjib Barua"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Rudra Singha",
                "B. Gadadhar Singha",
                "C. Pramatta Singha",
                "D. Siva Singha"
            ],
            "question": "The Dhodar Ali is constructed during the reign of __.",
            "answer": "B. Gadadhar Singha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Rudra Singha",
                "B. Gadadhar Singha",
                "C. Siva Singha",
                "D. Rajeswar Singha"
            ],
            "question": "The Jaysagar Tank was excavated under the reign of which of the following Kings?",
            "answer": "A. Rudra Singha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Khulna",
                "B. Sylhet",
                "C. Chittagong",
                "D. Sholashahar"
            ],
            "question": "The district which was separated from Assam and was given to East Pakistan in the year 1947 was __.",
            "answer": "B. Sylhet"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Nambor Reserve Forest",
                "B. Parashuram Kunda",
                "C. Orang Wildlife Sanctuary",
                "D. Manas Nationa Park"
            ],
            "question": "In Assam, a source of hot water spring is situated in __.",
            "answer": "A. Nambor Reserve Forest"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Biswa Singha",
                "B. Raghu Deva",
                "C. Naranarayan",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Kamakhya Temple was rebuilt by which one of the following Koch King?",
            "answer": "C. Naranarayan"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Non-Cooperation Movement",
                "B. Quit India Movement",
                "C. Civil Disobedience Movement",
                "D. Swadeshi Movement"
            ],
            "question": "Kanaklata Barua became a martyr of which one of the following national movements?",
            "answer": "B. Quit India Movement"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. India and Bhutan",
                "B. India and China",
                "C. India and Bangladesh",
                "D. India and Burma"
            ],
            "question": "The Patkai Bum range makes the boundary between __.",
            "answer": "D. India and Burma"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Parashuram Kunda",
                "B. Dekiakhowa Namghar",
                "C. Hajo",
                "D. Barpeta"
            ],
            "question": "Which one of the following places is the confluence of three highly revered pilgrimage for the Hindu, Muslim and Buddhists?",
            "answer": "C. Hajo"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jia Bharali",
                "B. Dikhow",
                "C. Subansiri",
                "D. Brahmaputra"
            ],
            "question": "Siang, joined by Lohit and Dibang makes which of the following rivers?",
            "answer": "D. Brahmaputra"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Pani Dihing",
                "B. Pobitora",
                "C. Laokhowa",
                "D. Chakrashila"
            ],
            "question": "Which Wildlife Sanctuary of Assam boasts of the golden langur?",
            "answer": "D. Chakrashila"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Garhgaon",
                "B. Charaideo",
                "C. Jorhat",
                "D. Sivsagar"
            ],
            "question": "Which one was the first capital of Ahom Kingdom in Assam?",
            "answer": "B. Charaideo"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 430 sq. km",
                "B. 500 sq. km",
                "C. 390 sq. km",
                "D. 720 sq. km"
            ],
            "question": "The area of Kaziranga National Park is approximately ___.",
            "answer": "A. 430 sq. km"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Asian hog deer",
                "B. Pygmy hog",
                "C. Asiatic wild buffalo",
                "D. Sangai deer"
            ],
            "question": "About 91% of world population of a particular animal species found in Kaziranga National Park is which one of the following?",
            "answer": "B. Pygmy hog"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 79 %",
                "B. 89 %",
                "C. 99 %",
                "D. 75 %"
            ],
            "question": "___ of the total production of Muga, the Golden Silk, in the world, Assam produces.",
            "answer": "C. 99 %"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Manas",
                "B. Kaziranga",
                "C. Pobitora",
                "D. Nameri"
            ],
            "question": "In which of the following National Parks/Wildlife Sanctuaries, the density of rhino population is the highest?",
            "answer": "C. Pobitora"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Karbi Anglong district",
                "B. Dima Hasao district",
                "C. Goalpara district",
                "D. Dhubri district"
            ],
            "question": "The highest concentration of forest in the State of Assam occurs in __.",
            "answer": "A. Karbi Anglong district"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jorhat",
                "B. Sivasagar",
                "C. Golaghat",
                "D. Dhemaji"
            ],
            "question": "Pani Dihing Bird Sanctuary is located in which one of the following districts?",
            "answer": "B. Sivasagar"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Kanaklata Barua",
                "B. Kamala Miri",
                "C. Kushal Konwar",
                "D. Maniram Dewan"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first martyr of 1942 Revolution in Assam?",
            "answer": "A. Kanaklata Barua"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Ahom King",
                "B. King of Burma",
                "C. Kachari King",
                "D. Chutiya King"
            ],
            "question": "The Treaty of Yandaboo signed between East India Company and which one of the following?",
            "answer": "B. King of Burma"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Phulaguri Dhawa",
                "B. Patharughat Raijmel",
                "C. Battle of Itakhuli",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "The first Peasant Uprising against the British was known as?",
            "answer": "A. Phulaguri Dhawa"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1788",
                "B. 1769",
                "C. 1777",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "The first phase of Moamoria Rebellion was started in __.",
            "answer": "B. 1769"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1922",
                "B. 1925",
                "C. 1928",
                "D. 1911"
            ],
            "question": "In which year Gopinath Bordoloi was arrested for taking part in the freedom movement?",
            "answer": "A. 1922"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Mishing",
                "B. Rabha",
                "C. Tiwa",
                "D. Bodo"
            ],
            "question": "In addition to Assamese, which other language from the State is included in the Eight Schedule of the Indian Constitution?",
            "answer": "D. Bodo"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 9th",
                "B. 12th",
                "C. 26th",
                "D. 14th"
            ],
            "question": "The rank of Assam in literacy among the States of India is __.",
            "answer": "C. 26th"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1863",
                "B. 1866",
                "C. 1852",
                "D. 1861"
            ],
            "question": "The Phulaguri uprising was take place in which year?",
            "answer": "D. 1861"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1991",
                "B. 1999",
                "C. 1994",
                "D. 1992"
            ],
            "question": "When Bhupen Hazarika had been awarded with Dadasaheb Phalke Award?",
            "answer": "D. 1992"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sonai Rupai (Sonitpur)",
                "B. Joypur (Dibrugarh)",
                "C. Sessa (Dibrugarh)",
                "D. Manas (Kokrajhar)"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following places is the site of rain forest in Assam and in which District?",
            "answer": "B. Joypur (Dibrugarh)"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Nabin Chandra Bordoloi",
                "B. Tarunram Phukan",
                "C. Kuladhar Saikia",
                "D. Liladhar Baruah"
            ],
            "question": "Who among the following from Assam joined the famous Dandi March?",
            "answer": "D. Liladhar Baruah"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 15th August, 1985",
                "B. 26th Janury, 1986",
                "C. 15th August, 1986",
                "D. 15th August, 1990"
            ],
            "question": "The historic Assam Accord was signed on ___.",
            "answer": "A. 15th August, 1985"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bodo",
                "B. Khasis",
                "C. Mising",
                "D. Naga"
            ],
            "question": "Ali-Aai-Ligang is an agri-based festival celebrated by the",
            "answer": "C. Mising"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 31st January",
                "B. 31st July",
                "C. 31st August",
                "D. 31st December"
            ],
            "question": "\"Me-Dum-Me-Phi\" festival is celebrated annually on ___.",
            "answer": "A. 31st January"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 13th January",
                "B. 4th April",
                "C. 8th September",
                "D. 1st October"
            ],
            "question": "Assam Police Day observed on ___.",
            "answer": "D. 1st October"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Karimganj",
                "B. Kamrup Metro",
                "C. Jorhat",
                "D. Golaghat"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam has been declared as first tobacco free district?",
            "answer": "C. Jorhat"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1946",
                "B. 1964",
                "C. 1932",
                "D. 1952"
            ],
            "question": "In which year was the Bodo Sahitya Shabha founded?",
            "answer": "D. 1952"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bhabendra Nath Saikia",
                "B. Dr Bhupen Hazarika",
                "C. Bidyut chakraborty",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Who directed the Assamese Film 'Shakuntala'?",
            "answer": "B. Dr Bhupen Hazarika"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Joymoti",
                "B. Indramalati",
                "C. Monumoti",
                "D. Siraj"
            ],
            "question": "Which one was the second film directed by Jyotiprasad Agarwala?",
            "answer": "B. Indramalati"
        }
    ]
}